[Music]
it was a quiet evening at the cottage
yesterday the days are quickly growing
darker and already several of my more
delicate flowers have been taken by an
early morning frost
i try to spend at least half an hour
reading every night and lately the days
have been so much shorter i've embraced
lighting candles
i remember as a literature student in
ireland i read about how people used
tallow candles in the past they were
made of animal fat and smelled horrible
consequently paraffin and other types of
wax were much preferred and eventually
replaced it
i'm quite grateful i can let my beeswax
tapers and that my home smells like
roasted honey instead of animal fat
[Music]
i find that using softer lights this
time of year helped connect me to the
season bringing more of an awareness on
how things are changing how it is
affecting the plants and animals it is a
harbinger of the coldest half of the
year a warning to the natural world to
prepare and haste as time is running out
over here the cottonwoods are some of
the first to shed their leaves
i think of them as having quite cautious
personalities much like my own
the moment things seem overly dry or at
the slightest hint of a frost they begin
to diminish drop their leaves and grow
dormant
the other trees soon follow suit and the
little animals busily prepare their food
stores
i've said goodbye to many birds in this
area gone to warmer climates until the
spring
for once i'm not jealous of them since
after a hot rainless summer i am
welcoming the cold
so is my dog who loves being outdoors
this time of year as he does not get
overheated
[Music]
okay
so
[Music]
in the spirit of the changing seasons i
thought i'd create some new decorations
for my home
recently i've been reading a lot about
old photography techniques from the past
my interest was peaked since i spent so
much more time using my camera this year
the technique of making blueprints also
known as cianotypes is one that
originated over a hundred years ago
after its invention a woman named anna
adkins became known for using the
technique in making shadowgraphs of
algae
the process has a fascinating history
and was still in use in some lines of
work up until modern printers became
popular
nowadays the technique is preserved by
artists and photographers interested in
the niche and their professional ciano
types are no doubt much better than my
own amateur attempts however it is so
much fun to try new things and through
that relive more positive aspects of the
past
[Music]
now and then i get comments on my videos
comparing how we live today to those in
the past often romanticizing an era
before technology and industrialization
took over
while there definitely has been a lot
lost through these transitions and many
tragedies in the process
i believe much has also been gained
depending on how you look at it
as someone who loves history and
learning about the past through my own
process of discovery i began to deeply
value living not only in my specific
location but in this century
for example my mother is not white and
she and my father would have struggled
to have their marriage legally
recognized in the u.s up until the 60s
my existence wouldn't be guaranteed at
any other time and if i had i would have
not been raised bilingual or probably
proud of my heritage
neither could i have so easily gone to
university and started my own business
i do not romanticize the past but i do
think it is full of rich stories that we
need to know
and i find nothing more fascinating than
learning about the daily lives of people
in any era much like we are fascinated
with how other people live today
it connects us to one another and trying
out this technique was a wonderful way
to relate with other creatives who lived
long ago and also liked experimenting
with art
[Music]
do
i will share some of my favorite books
about history in the description bar as
well as details on how to make your own
ciano type
this was so much fun and i encourage you
to try this technique out as the
materials are affordable and can be used
on fabric as well as paper
de san do te una noche gena de pas e
suenos
sending my love
[Music]
you